Guide to the Eleanor Robson Belmont Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Eleanor Robson Belmont Papers
1851-1979.
Belmont, Eleanor Robson, 1879-1979.
33 linear ft (ca. 11,500 items in 37 boxes, 159 volumes, 1 oversize folder, & 1 oversize box).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079125
Belmont (1878-1979) was an American actress and a prominent public figure. The collection includes correspondence, subject files, and personal materials.
Biogprahical Note
Eleanor Robson Belmont, actress socialite and philanthropist was born December 13, 1878 in Wigan Lancashire England to an actress mother and a musician father. Her father died when she was very young and her mother Madge Carr Cook remarried to the actor Augustus Cook immigrated to America. Eleanor was educated in American boarding schools after which she joined her mother Madge Carr Cook in the San Francisco-based Frawley Stock Company. She quickly graduated to starring roles while touring with the company. In 1900 she moved to New York where she was signed by the impresario George Tyler of Liebler and Company. She was a sensation acclaimed for her beauty her sweet rich speaking voice and her natural manner. Her greatest hit was Israel Zangwill's Merely Mary Ann in 1903. While playing the role in London, she captivated George Bernard Shaw who wrote Major Barbara for her. She was never able to play the part she inspired due to contractual obligations, but she continued to be a popular draw starring in Nurse Marjorie (1906), Salomy Jane (1907), and Dawn of Tomorrow (1909). In 1910, she left the stage to marry the banker, August Belmont.
After marriage, as she tells us in her autobiography Fabric of Memory, life became a "world of horses, polo, social events, new friends, civic interests, and farming." She supported her husband's pursuits including the Belmont racing stables, the construction of the New York Subway, and the Cape Cod Canal. Both Belmonts actively took part in the war effort in World War I. Mrs. Belmont was appointed to the American Red Cross and she courageously traveled dangerous waters to personally inspect the Red Cross overseas effort. After the war, she helped develop the peacetime American Red Cross.
Mrs. Belmont was widowed in 1924 but continued to be active in philanthropic causes. During the Great Depression, she raised funds with the Women's Committee of the Central Emergency Unemployment Relief Agency devoting special attention to the needs of the single working woman. When World War II broke out Mrs. Belmont again served the war effort through the Red Cross.
Mrs. Belmont maintained her interest in the theater. In 1931, she co-wrote and produced a play In the Next Room. Her theatrical fame and her training as an actress had contributed to her success as a fundraiser, and the performing arts remained one of her causes. She was especially fond of the Metropolitan Opera Company. In 1933, she became the first woman to sit on its Board of Directors. She founded the Metropolitan Opera Guild in 1935 as a permanent vehicle for raising money and as a basis of support. She lived to see the Opera emerge from the precarious financial predicament in which she found it to become a thriving, well-supported, well-attended institution.
Mrs. Belmont died at the age of 101 in 1979. On her hundredth birthday, December 13, 1978, she had told the New York Times that, "the secret to long life is no diet no special care nothing like that. It's doing what you want and doing it happily."
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, and papers reflecting Belmont's associations in the theatrical, musical, philanthropic, and social worlds. There are ten letters from Theodore Roosevelt, ten from George Bernard Shaw, twenty-two from Israel Zangwill, fifteen from Frances Hodgson Burnett, fifteen from Edith Wharton, and nine from Herbert Hoover, as well as letters from Anatole France, Mary Austin, Stephen Vincent Ben'et, Nicholas Murray Butler, Calvin Coolidge, Dwight David Eisenhower, Clyde Fitch, Harriet Ford, John Galsworthy, Ellen Glasgow, Yvette Guilbert, Amy Lowell, Archibald MacLeish, Edgar Lee Masters, John J. Pershing, Arthur Wing Pinero, William Howard Taft, and William Butler Yeats. In addition to the manuscripts of Mrs. Belmont's own writings, among them her autobiography FABRIC OF MEMORY, the collection contains a manuscript of Anatole France's "La Petite Ville de France" and a typescript of George Bernard Shaw's "Democracy and THE APPLE CART." There is also a considerable body of correspondence, scopecontents and reports of the organizations with which Mrs. Belmont was associated, including the American Shakespeare Festival Foundation, Educational Dramatic League, Metropolitan Opera Association, Motion Picture Research Council, and the Red Cross.
Arrangement
Selected materials cataloged; remainder arranged. The collection is arranged into four series:
Series I: Correspondence, 1851-1980
Subseries I.1: Cataloged Correspondence, 1851-1979
Subseries I.2: Arranged Correspondence, 1909-1980
Series II: Subject Files, 1904-1979
Series III: Personal and Biographical, 1906-1979
Series IV: Oversized Materials
Subjects
American Shakespeare Festival Foundation.; Educational Dramatic League.; Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.); Motion Picture Research Council.; American Red Cross.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Shaw, Bernard, 1856-1950.; Zangwill, Israel, 1864-1926.; Burnett, Frances Hodgson, 1849-1924.; Wharton, Edith, 1862-1937.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; France, Anatole, 1844-1924.; Austin, Mary.; Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1898-1943.; Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947.; Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Fitch, Clyde, 1865-1909.; Ford, Harriet, 1868-1949.; Galsworthy, John, 1867-1933.; Glasgow, Ellen Anderson Gholson, 1873-1945.; Guilbert, Yvette, 1865-1944.; Lowell, Amy, 1874-1925.; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982.; Masters, Edgar Lee, 1868-1950.; Pershing, John J. (John Joseph), 1860-1948.; Pinero, Arthur Wing, Sir, 1855-1934.; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930.; Yeats, W. B. (William Butler), 1865-1939.; Music--United States--Societies, etc.; Theater--United States--Societies, etc.; Opera--United States--Societies, etc.; Charities.; Motion picture industry.; Photographs.; Actresses.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
The following boxes are located off-site: Boxes 15-37. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
1962 M62 Belmont, Eleanor Robson Gift
Alternate Formats
Royal Cortissoz letters are on microfilm.
Gift of Eleanor Robson Belmont, 1962 & 1966; Bequest of Mrs Belmont, 1979.
Finding aid available in repository and online.
- Series I: Correspondence, 1851-1980
  The Correspondence is divided into Cataloged (1851-1979) and Arranged Correspondence (1908-1980.) The cataloged material is arranged individually by last name, then by date. The arranged material consists of general and family correspondence arranged alphabetically, then by date.
  - Subseries I.1 Cataloged Correspondence, 1851-1979
    The cataloged correspondence reflects Mrs. Belmont's associations with the theatrical, musical, philanthropic, political and social worlds. Included are letters from Anatole France, Winthrop Ames, Mary Austin, Stephen Vincent Benet, Rudolph Bing, Frances Hodgson Burnett, Nicholas Murray Butler, Calvin Coolidge, John Foster Dulles, Dwight David Eisenhower, Clyde Fitch, Kirsten Flagstad, Harriet Ford, John Glasworthy, Ellen Glasgow, Yvette Guilbert, William Averell Harriman, Herbert Hoover, Henry Cabot Lodge, Amy Lowell, Archibald MacLeish, Edgar Lee Masters, John J. Pershing, ARthur Wing Pinero, Eleanor Roosevelt, Theodore Roosevelt, George Bernard Shaw, William Howard Taft, and Israel Zangwill.
    - Adams, Maude, 1914 November 18 (Box 1)
    - Ainsley, Suzanne (Mrs. Henry), 1917-1918 (Box 1)
    - Akeley, Mary L. Jobe (Mrs. Carl), 1934 October 16 Albanese, Licia, 1973-1977 (Box 1)
    - Aldrich, Harriet (Mrs. Winthrop), December 22 (Box 1)
    - Alexander, John A. (Box 1)
    - Allen, Reginald, 1950 March 29 (Box 1)
    - Allenby, (Sir) Edmund Henry Hynman, 1st Viscount (Box 1)
      (1 photograph)
    - Allenby, Mabel, 1930 (Box 1)
    - Alma-Tadema, Lawrence, 1904 (Box 1)
    - Ames, Lucy (Mrs. Winthrop), 1923-1951 (Box 1)
    - Ames, Winthrop, 1906-1936 (Box 1)
    - Amory, Copley, Jr., 1938 October 5 (Box 1)
    - Amussen, Lorna Russell, May 19 (Box 1)
    - Anderson, Elizabeth Millbank, January 10 (Box 1)
    - Angell, James Rowland, 1935-1939 (Box 1)
    - Angell, Norman, 1932 April 21 (Box 1)
    - Anspacher, Louis K., 1920 July 11 (Box 1)
    - Appleton, Francis R., 1915-1925 (Box 1)
    - Archer, William, 1907-1923 (Box 1)
    - Arliss, George, 1937 September 26 (Box 1)
    - Astor, Brooke Russell (Mrs. Vincent), August 30 (Box 1)
    - Astor, Nancy Witcher Langhorne Astor, Viscountess, 1930-1955 (Box 1)
    - Astor, Waldorf, 2nd Viscount, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Auchincloss, Louis Stanton, 1964 November 9 (Box 1)
    - Auerbach, Joseph Smith, 1932-1943 (Box 1)
    - Austin, Mary, 1930-1939 (Box 1)
    - Austin, Mildred Lucas (Mrs. Warren R.), 1947 October 23 (Box 1)
    - Axson, Stockton, 1919 July 22 (Box 1)
    - Ayscough, Florence, October 15 (Box 1)
    - Babb, James T., 1944 May 17 (Box 1)
    - Bacon, Josephine Daskam (Mrs. Seldon), 1957 November 22 (Box 1)
    - Bacon, Martha (Mrs. Robert), November 30 (Box 1)
    - Baker, George P., 1927-1929 (Box 1)
    - Baker, Newton D., 1926-1942 (Box 1)
    - Bakhmeteff, Boris, 1938 October 5 (Box 1)
    - Balch, Earle, undated (Box 1)
    - Baldwin, Roger Nash, undated (Box 1)
    - Barry, Philip, 1930 May 24 (Box 1)
    - Barrymore, Ethel (Box 1)
    - Bataille, Henry, 1898 (Box 1)
    - Bates, Fred, November 3 (Box 1)
    - Batson, Eric J., 1958-1962 (Box 1)
    - Baylard, Edward J., 1932 September 20 (Box 1)
    - Beaux, Cecilia (Box 1)
    - Beebe, Elswyth Thane (Mrs. William), 1933-1953 (Box 1)
    - Beebe, William, 1930-1933 (Box 1)
    - Beekman, Margaret A., undated (Box 1)
    - Bellew, Kyrle, 1903-1910 (Box 1)
    - Belmont, August, undated (Box 2)
    - Belmont, Eleanor Robson, 1913-1960 (Box 2)
    - Belmont, Perry, 1941 November 12 (Box 2)
    - Benet, Rosemary Carr (Mrs. Stephen Vincent), undated (Box 2)
    - Benet, Stephen Vincent, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Bennett, Arnold, 1913 July 28 (Box 2)
    - Beringer, Aimee (Mrs. Oscar), September (Box 2)
    - Beylard, L.D., 1929 (Box 2)
    - Biancolli, Louis, 1952 December 7 (Box 2)
    - Bing, (Sir) Rudolf, 1949-1978 (Box 2)
    - Bingham, Millicent Todd (Mrs. Walter V.), undated (Box 2)
      (Washington)
    - Bird, Julia, 1958 June 24 (Box 2)
    - Bisphan, William, 1905 February 15 (Box 2)
    - Blackmore, Richard D., 1888 March 3 (Box 2)
    - Blaine, James G., 1933 October 11 (Box 2)
    - Blashfield, Edwin Howland, 1909-1922 (Box 2)
    - Bliss, Cornelius Newton, undated (Box 2)
    - Bliss, Lillian, 1930 (Box 2)
    - Bliss, Mildred (Mrs. Robert W.), 1929-1932 (Box 2)
    - Bliss, Zaidee (Mrs. Cornelius), undated (Box 2)
    - Bloom, Sol, 1912-1943 (Box 2)
    - Blossom, Henry, 1908 (Box 2)
    - Blum, Daniel, 1954 November 10 (Box 2)
    - Boles, Blanche, undated (Box 2)
    - Bolton, Frances P., 1934 October 8 (Box 2)
    - Bonham Carter, Violet, 1949 December 15 (Box 2)
    - Bori, Lucrezia, 1933-1952 (Box 2)
    - Bosworth, Welles, 1943 September 6 (Box 2)
    - Branscomb, Harvie, 1961 March 17 (Box 2)
    - Bridges-Adams, William, 1923-1930 (Box 2)
    - Brieux, Henri, undated (Box 2)
    - Brosio, Manlio, 1958 May 27 (Box 2)
    - Brown, Catherine Screvin Meredith (Mrs. John Mason), 1959 March 3 (Box 2)
    - Brown, Elmer Ellsworth, 1933 (Box 2)
    - Brown, Ivor, 1951-1952 (Box 2)
    - Brown, John Mason, 1939-1967 (Box 2)
    - Brown, Reginald Langdon, 1905 April 20 (Box 2)
    - Bryan, John Stewart, 1941 March 27 (Box 2)
    - Buchan, John, 1917-1934 (Box 2)
    - Bullard, Robert Lee, 1923-1924 (Box 2)
    - Bullen, Percy S., 1932 March 11 (Box 2)
    - Bundy, Harvey, 1957 December 3 (Box 2)
    - Burke, Arleigh Albert, 1960 January 13 (Box 2)
    - Burlingham, Charles Culp, 1937-1958 (Box 3)
    - Burnand, (Sir) Francis Cowley, 1904-1907 (Box 3)
    - Burnett, Constance (Mrs.Vivian), 1957 December 12 (Box 3)
    - Burnett, Frances Hodgson, 1907-1925 (Box 3)
    - Burnham, Clara Louise, 1909 November 15 (Box 3)
    - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1931-1937 (Box 3)
    - Butts, McCoskey, 1916 July 10 (Box 3)
    - Cadogan, Theodore (Mrs. Alexander), undated (Box 3)
    - Caine, Mary Hall, 1904 (Box 3)
    - Callender, May, February 13 (Box 3)
    - Calve, Emma, 1936 (Box 3)
    - Campbell, Beatrice Stella Tanner (Mrs. Patrick), 1913 (Box 3)
    - Campbell, Richard, 1934-1915 (Box 3)
    - Carey, Hugh L., 1978 November 27 (Box 3)
    - Carlisle, Leslie, 1925 March 24 (Box 3)
    - Carr, Joseph William Comyns, undated (Box 3)
    - Carrel, Alexis, 1937 (Box 3)
    - Carty, John J., 1924 February 13 (Box 3)
    - Carty, Marion Russel (Mrs. John J.), November 28 (Box 3)
    - Cecil of Chelwood, Robert Gascoyne-Cecil, Viscount, 1939 January 20 (Box 3)
    - Celler, Emmanuel, 1972 June -July (Box 3)
    - Chamberlain, Abbie, undated (Box 3)
    - Chamberlain, Ella, 1908 February 13 (Box 3)
    - Chanler, Winthrop, undated (Box 3)
    - Chapin, Katherine Garrison (Mrs. Francis Biddle), 1930-1957 (Box 3)
    - Chapman, Frank M., 1929 (Box 3)
    - Chapman, John Jay, 1915 April 11 (Box 3)
    - Choate, Joseph H., 1904-1914 (Box 3)
    - Clarke, George, August 20 (Box 3)
    - Clark, W.G., April 15 (Box 3)
    - Clarke, Joseph Ignatius Constantine, 1904 January 30 (Box 3)
    - Clarke, Thomas Shields, 1926 January (Box 3)
    - Clifford, Lucy Lane (Mrs. W.K.), November 25 (Box 3)
    - Cochran, Thomas, 1930 September 23 (Box 3)
    - Coghlan, Rose, undated (Box 3)
    - Cohan, George M., 1914 November 4 (Box 3)
    - Coleman, Charles Caryl, 1913-1924 (Box 3)
    - Colfax, Sybil, undated (Box 3)
    - Comstock, Ada Louise, 1931 March 3 (Box 3)
    - Conant, Isabel Fiske, May (Box 3)
    - Conkling, Alfred R., undated (Box 3)
    - Cook, Madge (Carr) Robson, 1903-1904 (Box 3)
    - Coolidge, Calvin, 1924 February 18 (Box 3)
    - Cornell, Katherine, 1923-1951 (Box 3)
    - Cortissoz, Royal, 1929-1943 (Box 3)
    - Cowles, Anna Roosevelt, 1923 April 16 (Box 3)
    - Crafts, Elizabeth, January 2 (Box 3)
    - Craigie, Pearl Mary Teresa, 1904 (Box 3)
    - Crane, Charles R., 1925-1929 (Box 3)
    - Crane, William H., undated (Box 3)
    - Crawford, Francis Marion, 1906-1908 (Box 3)
    - Cravath, Paul, 1934 August 30 (Box 3)
    - Crossman, Henrietta (Campbell), undated (Box 3)
    - Crothers, Rachel, 1955 (Box 3)
    - Cunard, Bache, undated (Box 3)
    - Cushman, Charlotte, March 3 (Box 3)
    - Cuthbert, Margaret, 1936 May 12 (Box 3)
    - Daly, Arnold, January 16 (Box 3)
    - Damrosch, Walter, 1924-1927 (Box 3)
    - Davis, Ellen B. (Mrs. John William), undated (Box 3)
    - Davis, John William, 1917-1955 (Box 4)
    - Davis, Mackie (Mrs. Norman H.), undated (Box 4)
    - Davis, Mary E., undated (Box 4)
    - Davis, Norman H., 1932-1943 (Box 4)
    - Davis, Richard Harding, 1908 (Box 4)
    - Davis, Ruby Hale, undated (Box 4)
    - Davison, Henry Pomeroy, 1918-1921 (Box 4)
    - Dawes, Caro D. (Mrs. Charles G.), 1918 March 7 (Box 4)
    - de Ivanowski, S., 1908 December 15 (Box 4)
    - De Koven, Anna Farwell (Mrs. Reginald), 1936 December 14 (Box 4)
    - Deland, Margaret Wade (Mrs. Lorin F.), 1907-1908 (Box 4)
    - Delano, William Adams, 1932-1952 (Box 4)
    - Denby, Edwin H., 1949 November 29 (Box 4)
    - Derby, Ethel Carew Roosevelt (Mrs. Richard), 1926-1975 (Box 4)
    - Derby, Richard, 1948 November 26 (Box 4)
    - Desmond-Fitzgerald, H.C., undated (Box 4)
    - Devine, Edward T., 1937 December 8 (Box 4)
    - De Wolfe, Elsie, 1917 (Box 4)
    - De Wolfe, Elsie Anderson and Elizabeth Marbury, 1904 September 6 (Box 4)
    - Dickens, Charles, 1863 December 4 (Box 4)
    - Dickens, Marie, March 9 (Box 4)
    - Dickens, Olive and Robert, 1904 (Box 4)
    - Dietz, Howard, 1952 December 29 (Box 4)
    - Dix, Dorothy, 1904 June 16 (Box 4)
    - Dix, Gertrude (Mrs. John Alden), 1911 June 10 (Box 4)
    - Dix, John Alden (1860-1928), 1911 (Box 4)
    - Dixon, Alexandra Ismene (Mrs. John Pierson), 1958-1960 (Box 4)
    - Dodge, Cleveland E., 1978 February 6 (Box 4)
    - Dodgson, Charles Lutwidge, 1883 August 16 (Box 4)
    - Douglas, Peggy (Mrs. Lewis), 1949 May 19 (Box 4)
    - Drew, George, 1961 June 19 (Box 4)
    - Drew, John, 1914 (Box 4)
    - Drogheda, Charles Garrett Ponsonby Moore, 11th Earl of, 1978 December 5 (Box 4)
    - Du Bois, Florence (Mrs.Guy Pene), 1940 January 7 (Box 4)
    - Duff-Gordon, Lady Lucie, undated (Box 4)
    - Duffy, Francis P., 1921 November 3 (Box 4)
    - Duggan, Stephen P., 1918 (Box 4)
    - Dulles, Alan, 1932-1961 (Box 4)
    - Dulles, Clover (Mrs. Allen), 1961 October 16 (Box 4)
    - Dulles, Janet (Mrs. John Foster), 1959 August 17 (Box 4)
    - Dulles, John Foster, 1953 (Box 4)
    - Dunn, Gano, 1930-1951 (Box 4)
    - Eames, Emma (Story), 1907-1915 (Box 5)
    - Easely, Ralph M., 1928-1932 (Box 5)
    - Eaton, Alice W. (Mrs.Frank), January 10 (Box 5)
    - Eaton, Rosemary, 1953 February 1 (Box 5)
    - Eccles, David, M.P., 1949 (Box 5)
    - Edison, Thomas Alva, undated (Box 5)
    - Egan, Maurice Francis, 1913-1921 (Box 5)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight David, 1947-1950 (Box 5)
    - Eisenhower, Mamie Doud, 1950 (Box 5)
    - Eliot, Thomas H., 1934 March 8 (Box 5)
    - Elliot, Walter, 1933 July 14 (Box 5)
    - Emerson, Guy, 1932-1940 (Box 5)
    - Emmet, Lydia F., April 2 (Box 5)
    - Erskine, John, 1926-1944 (Box 5)
    - Ervine, St. John, 1928-1957 (Box 5)
    - Esher, Eleanor, 1910-1917 (Box 5)
    - Fairchild, Roy, February 14 (Box 5)
    - Farrand, Beaux, 1948 July 8 (Box 5)
    - Farrand, Livingston, 1919 December 1 (Box 5)
    - Farrand, Max, September 7 (Box 5)
    - Farrar, Geraldine, 1937 October 22 (Box 5)
    - Farrar, John, 1934-1972 (Box 5)
    - Farrar, Margaret (Mrs. John), 1957-1976 (Box 5)
    - Faulkner, Barry, undated (Box 5)
    - Faulkner, Ellen, undated (Box 5)
    - Faulks, Theodosia Garrison (Mrs. Frederic), undated (Box 5)
    - Faversham, William, 1914 October 28 (Box 5)
    - Finletter, Gretchen Blaine Damrosch (Mrs. Thomas K), 1957 November (Box 5)
    - Finletter, Thomas K., undated (Box 5)
    - Finley, John Huston, 1914-1939 (Box 5)
    - Finley, Martha (Mrs. John), 1934-1947 (Box 5)
    - Fiske, Minnie Madern, 1919-1924 (Box 5)
    - Fitch, Clyde, 1904-1905 (Box 5)
    - Flagstad, Kirsten, 1952-1961 (Box 5)
    - Fletcher, Constance, 1904-1905 (Box 5)
    - Flexner, Anne Crawford, 1923-1924 (Box 5)
    - Florinsky, Michael T., 1931 June 3 (Box 5)
    - Flower, Archibald, 1926-1936 (Box 5)
    - Flower, Florence, 1930-1936 (Box 5)
    - Flower, Thomas, 1935 July 12 (Box 5)
    - Flynn, Martin H., 1914 February 18 (Box 5)
    - Fontanne, Lynn, 1975 February 10 (Box 5)
    - Forbes, James, 1933 October 21 (Box 5)
    - Forbes-Robertson, Beatrice, December 15 (Box 5)
    - Forbes-Robertson, Sir Johnston and Gertrude Elliott, 1904 September 8 (Box 5)
    - Ford, Harriet, 1908-1941 (Box 5)
    - Foreman, Clark, 1934 July 1 (Box 6)
    - Forrest, Carolyn, February 16 (Box 6)
    - Fosdick, Harry Emerson, 1927-1938 (Box 6)
    - Foss, Eugene Noble, 1913 June 26 (Box 6)
    - France, Anatole, April 19 (Box 6)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1937-1960 (Box 6)
    - Franks, Barbara, 1951 November 24 (Box 6)
    - Fraser, Laura Gardin, 1954 February 17 (Box 6)
    - French, John Denton, 1922 May 22 (Box 6)
    - Frick, Grace, 1951 January 20 (Box 6)
    - Furman, Virginia D.H., 1917 June 15 (Box 6)
    - Gabrilowitsch, Clara Clemens, 1918 August 18 (Box 6)
    - Gade, Ruth Sibley (Mrs. John), undated (Box 6)
    - Gade, John Allyne, undated (Box 6)
    - Gale, Zona, 1921-1928 (Box 6)
    - Gallico, Paul, 1956 February 21 (Box 6)
    - Gallico, Pauline (Mrs. Paul), 1952 March 15 (Box 6)
    - Galsworthy, John, 1913 May 14 (Box 6)
    - Gannon, Robert Ignatius, 1957-1976 (Box 6)
    - Gardner, Isabella S., February 24 (Box 6)
    - Garrigue, Esperanza, 1938 October 17 (Box 6)
    - Garrigue, Evelyn, 1909 April 18 (Box 6)
    - Gary, Elbridge H., 1909 February 1 (Box 6)
    - George, Grace (Brady), undated (Box 6)
    - Gerard, James W., 1921 December 1 (Box 6)
    - Gerson, Virginia, 1920-1925 (Box 6)
    - Gerard, James W., 1934 November 3 (Box 6)
    - Gibson, Charles Dana, 1919-1930 (Box 6)
    - Gibson, Irene (Mrs. Charles Dana), undated (Box 6)
    - Gifford, Walter Sherman, 1943 January 1 (Box 6)
    - Gilder, Jeanette L., 1904 March 24 (Box 6)
    - Gildersleeve, Virginia Crocheron, 1918 May 19 (Box 6)
    - Gill, Basil, undated (Box 6)
    - Gillette, William, 1904-1932 (Box 6)
    - Gillmore, Frank, 1927-1930 (Box 6)
    - Gilman, Lawrence, 1936-1939 (Box 6)
    - Glasgow, Ellen, 1905 (Box 6)
    - Glass, Carter, 1935 June 22 (Box 6)
    - Gluck, Alma (Zimbalist), undated (Box 6)
    - Gogarty, Oliver St. John, undated (Box 6)
    - Goldsmith, Sophie L. (Mrs. Maurice), 1958 April 18 (Box 6)
    - Goodman, Jules Eckert, undated (Box 6)
    - Goodrich, Annie W., 1949 August 12 (Box 6)
    - Goodrich, Arthur, 1927 February 4 (Box 6)
    - Graf, Herbert, 1959 December 12 (Box 6)
    - Graf, Herbert and Lisa, 1958-1960 (Box 6)
    - Graham, George M., 1918 June 12 (Box 6)
    - Granger, Annie W. (Mrs. Arthur), 1940 December 21 (Box 6)
    - Grant, Percy Stickney, 1910-1925 (Box 6)
    - Grant, Robert, 1906 March 7 (Box 6)
    - Granville-Barker, Harley, 1915 (Box 6)
    - Granville-Barker, Lillah (Mrs. Harley), 1915 May 24 (Box 6)
    - Graves, Clothilde, 1900-1906 (Box 6)
    - Grayson, Cary T., 1922 June 15 (Box 6)
    - Green, William, 1932 August 15 (Box 6)
    - Greenway, George Lauder, 1956 December 28 (Box 6)
    - Grew, Joseph Clark, 1926-1937 (Box 6)
    - Grey, Charles Robert, 1933 July 20 (Box 6)
    - Grey, David, 1924 December 12 (Box 6)
    - Gruenther, Alfred M., 1957 November 19 (Box 6)
    - Guggenheim, Solomon R., 1939 May 15 (Box 6)
    - Guilbert, Yvette, 1920-1921 (Box 6)
    - Gunther, John, January 24 (Box 6)
    - Guthrie, Tyrone, 1960 February 22 (Box 6)
    - Hadley, Henry K., undated (Box 6)
    - Hagerdorn, Hermann, Director Roosevelt Memorial Assoc., 1943-1948 (Box 6)
    - Hall, Gertrude, 1937 June 5 (Box 6)
    - Hamilton, Edith, August 5 (Box 6)
    - Hammond, Emily V., January 15 (Box 6)
    - Hampden, Walter, 1928 June 14 (Box 6)
    - Hand, Frances (Mrs. Learned), 1953 (Box 6)
    - Hand, Learned, 1952 November 10 (Box 6)
    - Hannigan, Angela M., 1953 September 22 (Box 6)
    - Hapgood, Norman, 1904 October 5 (Box 6)
    - Harbaugh, William H., 1958-1959 (Box 6)
    - Harbord, James G., 1932-1944 (Box 6)
    - Harriman, Corinne, 1924 December 16 (Box 6)
    - Harriman, Edward Roland, November 13 (Box 6)
    - Harriman, Florence Jaffray (Mrs. J. Borden), 1933-1957 (Box 6)
    - Harriman, Mary (Mrs. Edward H.), 1917-1932 (Box 6)
    - Harriman, William Averell, 1954-1978 (Box 6)
    - Harrison, Sydney, 1925 January 1 (Box 7)
    - Harter, Unia, 1925 April 18 (Box 7)
    - Hartfield, Joseph Manuel, 1931 March 23 (Box 7)
    - Harvey, James Clarence, undated (Box 7)
    - Hastings, Helen, undated (Box 7)
    - Hastings, Thomas, 1909 May 2 (Box 7)
    - Hayes, Ralph, 1928-1956 (Box 7)
    - Healy, Julia Davis (Mrs. Charles), 1955-1958 (Box 7)
    - Heinemann, William, 1904 January 20 (Box 7)
    - Helburn, Theresa, 1923-1951 (Box 7)
    - Henderson, Archibald, 1936-1957 (Box 7)
    - Herrick, Myron T., 1920 March 20 (Box 7)
    - Hess, Myra, 1922 April 14 (Box 7)